# JIAHAO JI

Beihang University, Beijing, China

jiahaoji@buaa.edu.cn | +86 15600537533 | Homepage: https://echo-ji.github.io/academicpages

# Research Interest

My research interests include spatio-temporal data mining, interpretable machine learning and urban computing. In particular, I have passion in designing (1) interpretable and robust algorithms for mining spatio-temporal data and graph data and (2) models for learning from these data types for various applications such as transportation, hazardous chemicals, epidemic, etc.

# EDUCATION

Beihang University

Beijing, China

Ph.D. student in Technology of Computer Application, GPA: 3.8/4.0

Sep. 2019 - June 2024

Core Courses: Data Science Foundations, Machine Learning, Principles of Artificial Intelligence

Beihang University

Beijing, China

Bachelor of Computer Science and Technology, GPA: 3.7/4.0

Sep. 2015 - June 2019

Core Courses: Introduction of Data Mining, Principles of Compilers, Operating System

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

BIGSCity Lab, Beihang University

Beijing, China

Research Assistant

Seq. 2019 - June 2024

Supervisor: Prof. Jingyuan Wang; Research: Urban Computing, Data Mining, Interpretability

DMAL Lab, Nanyang Technological University

Singapore

Visiting Ph.D. Student

Feb. 2023 - Jan. 2024

Supervisor: **Prof. Cheng Long**; Research: Physics-Guided Spatio-Temporal Prediction

JD Intelligent Cities Research

Beijing, China

Research Internship

Mar. 2021 - Jan. 2023

Supervisor: Dr. Yu Zheng and Junbo Zhang, Research: Trajectory Mining, Flow Prediction

#### Honors & Awards

Chinese Government Scholarship: 2022

CETC The 14TH Research Institute Glarun Scholarship: 2022, 2020 Scholarships for Postgraduate Studies: the First Prize, 2022, 2021, 2020, 2019

Huawei Scholarship: 2021 CASC Scholarship: 2020

Outstanding Freshman Scholarship: 2019

National Encouragement Scholarship: 2018, 2017, 2016

Innovation and Entrepreneurship Scholarship of the MIIT: 2018 ASC18 - ASC Student Supercomputer Challenge: the First Prize, 2018 COMAP's Mathematical Contest in Modeling: Meritorious Winner, 2018

# **PUBLICATIONS**

1. **J. Ji**, J. Wang, C. Huang, J. Wu, B. Xu, Z. Wu, J. Zhang and Y. Zheng, "Spatio-temporal self-supervised learning for traffic flow prediction," in *Thirty-seventh AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI'23)*, 2023. (CCF A)

- 2. J. Wang, J. Ji, Z. Jiang, and L. Sun, "Traffic flow prediction based on spatiotemporal potential energy fields," *IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering (TKDE)*, 2022. (CCF A, IF=9.235)
- 3. J. Ji, J. Wang, J. Wu, B. Han, J. Zhang, and Y. Zheng, "Precision CityShield against hazardous chemicals threats via location mining and self-supervised learning," in *Proceedings of the 28th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining* (KDD'22), 2022, pp. 3072-3080. (CCF A)
- 4. **J. Ji**, J. Wang, Z. Jiang, Jiawei Jiang, Hu Zhanng, "STDEN: Towards physics-guided neural networks for traffic flow prediction," in *Thirty-Sixth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence* (**AAAI'22**), vol. 36, no. 4, pp. 4048-4056, 2022. (**CCF A, acceptance rate=15%**)
- 5. **J. Ji**, J. Wang, Z. Jiang, J. Ma, and H. Zhang, "Interpretable spatiotemporal deep learning model for traffic flow prediction based on potential energy fields," in *IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM'20)*, 2020, pp. 1076-1081. (CCF B, acceptance rate=9.9%)
- J. Wang, H. Shi, J. Ji, X. Lin, H. Tian, "High-Resolution Data on Human Behavior for Effective COVID-19 Policy-Making — Wuhan City, Hubei Province, China, January 1–February 29, 2020," in China CDC Weekly, 2023.
- 7. Z. Wu, L. Wu, S. Song, **J. Ji**, B. Zou, Z. Li, and X. He, "DialCSP: A two-stage attention-based model for customer satisfaction prediction in e-commerce customer service," in *Joint European Conference on Machine Learning and Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML PKDD'22)*, 2022. (CCF B)
- 8. Z. Wu, X. Yu, M. Chen, L. Wu, **J. Ji**, and Z. Li, "Enhancing New Intent Discovery via Robust Neighbor-based Contrastive Learning," *The 24th INTERSPEECH Conference (Interspeech'23)*, 2023. (CCF C)